So today is a day when you have to promise Me
Dakle, danas je dan kada morate mi obećati
that you’ll meditate every night,
da ćete meditirati svake noći,
every evening, maybe in the morning also.
svaku večer, možda ujutro također.
Whenever it is possible if you can go into a meditative mood,
Kad god je to moguće, ako možete ući u meditativno raspoloženje,
you are in contact with this Divine power.
vi ste u kontaktu s tom Božanskom snagom.
Then, whatever is good for you, whatever good for your society,
Tada sve što je dobro za vas, što je dobro za vaše društvo,
for your country, all is done by this Divine power.
za vašu zemlju, sve je to učinila ova Božanska moć.
You don’t have to overpower the Divine power,
Vi ne morate nadvladati Božansku moć,
you don’t have to order, you don’t have to ask,
ne morate naređivati, ne morate pitati,
just if you meditate you are one with this All-pervading Power
Samo ako meditirate vi ste jedno s ovom sveprožimajućom moći
which is another great blessing to us.
što je još jedan veliki blagoslov za nas.
Unless and until your Sahasrara is opened
Ako i dokle god vaša Sahasrara nije otvorena
all the blessings of the Divine power cannot come to you, cannot.
sve blagodati Božanske moći ne mogu doći k vama, ne mogu.
Maybe you might get some money, you might get some jobs,
Možda ste možda dobili neki novac, možda ćete dobiti neke poslove,
you might get this and that.
možda dobijete ovo ili ono.
But your own development is only possible when you meditate
No, vaš vlastiti razvoj je moguć samo kad meditirate
and your Sahasrara is completely open and open to truth.
i vaša Sahasrara je potpuno otvorena i otvorena za istinu.
Now the truth is that this Divine power is compassion, is love.
Sada, Istina je da je ova Božanska moć suosjećanje, ljubav.
This is the truth.
Ovo je istina.
They say God is love and God is truth,
Kažu da je Bog ljubav i Bog je istina,
so the equation has to be made that truth is love and love is truth.
pa jednadžba mora biti da je istina ljubav i ljubav je istina.
But it’s not a truth that, as you have for your own children,
Ali to nije istina da je, kao što imate za svoju djecu,
you have for your family, attached.
imate za svoju obitelj, vezanost.
Attached love is not truth.
Vezana ljubav nije istina.
If you are attached to somebody
Ako ste vezani za nekoga
then you never see the bad points of that person.
tada ne vidite loše točke te osobe.
If you are angry with somebody,
Ako ste ljuti na nekoga,
then you can never see the good points of that person.
onda nikada ne možete vidjeti dobre strane te osobe.
But it’s a complete detached love
No, to je potpuna nevezana ljubav
and that love is extremely powerful
i ta je ljubav vrlo moćna
because whenever you project that love to anyone,
jer kad god projektujete tu ljubav nekome,
you’ll be surprised, the problems of that person will be solved,
vi ćete biti iznenađeni, problemi te osobe će se riješiti,
his personality will improve,
njegova ličnost će poboljšati,
everything will work out in a very big way and his life will be changed.
sve će se razriješiti na vrlo velik način i njegov život će se promijeniti.
But if you’re attached to anything whatsoever,
Ali, ako ste vezani za bilo što,
that attachment itself causes problems and doesn’t allow Sahaj to grow.
sama ta vezanost uzrokuje probleme i ne dopušta Sahađ rasti.
This attachment could be any kind, for example,
Ova vezanost može biti bilo kakva, na primjer,
you can be attached to your country, attached to your society,
možete biti vezani za svoju zemlju, vezani za vaše društvo,
attached to your family, it can be of any kind.
vezani na svoju obitelj, to može biti bilo koje vrste.
But when Sahasrara is open, you’ll learn one thing, is detachment.
Ali kad Sahastrara je otvorena, naučit ćete jednu stvar. To je nevezanost.
It just happens that you get detached.
Jednostavno se desi da ste nevezani.
Though, I mean, you are not running away.
Iako, mislim, vi ne bežite.
As it is in Sahaja Yoga we don’t believe in people who run away
Kao što je u Sahaja Yogi mi ne vjerujemo u ljude koji beže daleko
from society and go to Himalayas, all that I call escapism,
iz društva i idu na Himalaje, sve što ja nazivam bežanje,
that is not the point.
to nije poanta.
What happens is that you are there, you see everyone,
Što se događa je da ste tu, možete vidjeti sve,
you watch everyone, you know everyone,
gledate sve, znate sve,
you are close to everyone, but you are a detached person.
vi ste blizu svima, ali vi ste nevezana osoba.
It’s a state of mind that you achieve when Sahasrara is open.
To je stanje svijesti koje ste postigli kada je Sahastrara otvorena.
In that state you are dealing with people,
U tom stanju bavite se ljudima,
you are dealing with problems, you are dealing with situations,
bavite se problemima, bavite se situacijama,
but you are not involved in it, there’s no involvement;
ali niste uključeni u to, nema uključenosti;
and that involvement which you had before
i ta uključenost koju ste imali prije
can never give a complete insight, what is happening,
nikada ne može dati potpuni uvid, što se događa,
what the truth is, about any situation.
što je istina, o bilo kojoj situaciji.
So this detachment helps.
Dakle, ovo odvajanje pomaže.
The greatest thing of the detachment is that you are not affected.
Najveća stvar nevezanosti je da niste pogođeni.
No use saying that, “oh you are not affected,
Nema smisla reći: „Oh ti nisi pogođena
Mother, so how can you feel for another person?
Majko, pa kako onda se možeš suosjećati za drugu osobu?
How can you have compassion for another person?
Kako možeš imati suosjećanja za druge osobe?
Because if you feel for another person
Jer ako se suosjećate za drugu osobu
then only you can solve the problem”.
samo onda možete riješiti problem”.
But this feeling that you have is again a kind of an attachment.
Ali taj osjećaj koji imate je opet neka vrsta vezanosti.
It is not a real feeling, because it doesn’t help.
To nije pravi osjećaj, jer to ne pomaže.
The person is crying, you are also crying,
Osoba plače, također i ti plačeš,
the person is trouble, you are also in trouble.
Osoba je u nevolji, vi ste također u nevolji.
And this does not help that person, nor will it help you.
I to ne pomaže toj osobi, niti će vama pomoći.
So to have detached in no way means
Dakle biti nevezan nipošto ne znači
you do not feel for another person.
da se ne suosjećate za drugu osobu.
You do feel.
Vi zaista osjećate.
You feel the agony of that person, the trouble of that person,
Osjećate agoniju te osobe, problem te osobe,
of the whole society sometimes and of the whole country.
cijelog društva ponekad i cijele zemlje.
But that your feeling is so detached
Ali tako da je vaš osjećaj tako nevezan
that the All-pervading Power takes over.
da je sveprožimajuća moć preuzima.
First we must have full faith
Prvo moramo imati potpunu vjeru
in the capability of this All-pervading Power.
u sposobnost ove sveprožimajuće moći.
As soon as you are detached.
Čim ste nevezani
You say, “You do it” - finished.
Ti kažeš: „Ti to učini” - gotovo.
Once you say that, “You are going to do it,
Čim kažete: „Ti ćeš to učiniti,
it’s You who is going to do it,”
ti si ta koja će to učiniti”
whole thing changes completely.
Cijela stvar potpuno se mijenja.
Because you transfer all your responsibilities, all your problems,
Zato što prenosite sve svoje odgovornosti, sve vaše probleme,
to this Divine power, which is so powerful,
ovoj Božanskoj sili, koja je tako moćna,
which is so capable, which can work out anything.
koja je tako sposobna, koja može uraditi bilo šta.
So whenever you think that this problem you are going to solve,
Dakle, kad god mislite da je to problem koji ćete riješiti,
you are the one who’s going to do it,
vi ste ti koji će to učiniti,
then, alright, the Divine power says: “Alright, try your luck.”
onda, u redu, Božanska moć kaže: „U redu, okušaj svoju sreću.”
But if you can really put this problem to the Divine power,
Ali ako stvarno možete staviti ovaj problem božanskoj moći,
it will work out.
to će se razrešiti.
We have all kinds of problems in Sahaja Yoga,
Imamo sve vrste problema u Sahaja Yogi,
especially when we find that people
pogotovo kad vidimo da ljudi
are not so much attracted to Sahaja Yoga,
nisu toliko privučeni Sahaja Yogi,
they are few in number then you feel very bad about it.
oni su malobrojni, onda se osjećate jako loše zbog toga.
But have you tried to meditate on this point,
No, jeste li pokušali meditirati po tom pitanju,
and have you tried to put this problem to the Divine power?
i jeste li pokušali staviti ovaj problem na Božansku moć?
Why should we worry?
Zašto bismo trebali brinuti?
When we have Divine power available through our Sahasrara,
Kada imamo Božansku moć dostupnu putem naše Sahastrare,
why should we worry?
Zato bismo trebali brinuti?
Why should we think about it?
Zašto bismo trebali razmišljati o tome?
Just leave it to the Divine power.
Samo to ostavite božanskoj moći.
If that is possible, if that you can achieve,
Ako je to moguće, ako to možete postići,
which is very difficult for human beings,
što je vrlo teško za ljudska bića,
because they live with their ego,
jer žive sa svojim egom,
they live with their conditionings;
žive sa svojim uvjetovanjima;
but if that attachment to all these things goes away,
ali ako ta vezanost za sve ove stvari nestane,
then what you do is just leave things to this power.
tada ono što radite je samo prepuštanje stvari ovoj moći.
Krishna has said in His Gita:
Krišna je rekao u svojoj Giti:
“Sarva dharmanam parityajya mamekam sharanam vraja”
„Sarva dharmanam parityajya mamekam sharanam vraja”
“Forget about all your dharmas”.
„Zaboravite sve svoje dharme”.
Dharmas means, He means, meaning that we have a dharma of a wife,
Dharmas znači, on misli, znači da imamo dharmu supruge,
of a husband, of a member of the society,
od muža, člana društva,
all of them have their own dharma.
svi oni imaju svoje dharme.
But He says “Leave them. And leave it, them to Me and I’ll manage.”
No, on kaže: „Ostavite ih. I ostavite ih meni, i ja ću upravljati.”
This is it what we have to learn, is to say that
To je ono što moramo naučiti, jeste da
“It’s this Divine power which will solve our problems.”
„Božanska snaga je ta koja će riješiti naše probleme.”
As human beings it’s a very difficult state
Kao ljudska bića, to je vrlo teško stanje
and this state only can be achieved through meditation.
a to stanje samo se može postići kroz meditaciju.
But I’m not saying that you go on meditating for hours together.
Ali ja ne govorim da meditirate satima i satima.
That’s not necessary.
To nije potrebno.
But with full faith in yourself and in the Divine power.
No, s punom vjerom u sebe i u Božansku moć.
If you work it out, I’m sure it’s not difficult
Ako to uradite, sigurna sam da nije teško
to rise to that state of consciousness.
uzdići se u to stanje svijesti.
That is what we have to achieve.
To je ono što moramo postići.
It’s possible for men as well as for women.
To je moguće za muškarce kao i za žene.
They don’t have to think: “How can we, Mother, do it after all?”
Oni ne moraju razmišljati: „Kako možemo, majko, zaista to uraditi?”
You see, all such people are no good for Sahaja Yoga.
Vidite, svi takvi ljudi nisu dobri za Sahaja Yogu.
Those who have diffidence about themselves cannot do anything.
Oni koji imaju sumnju u sebe ne mogu ništa učiniti.
But those who are surrendered and those who think they can do it,
No, oni koji su se predali i onih koji misle da to mogu učiniti,
can manage all this transfer of their power to the Divine power.
mogu obaviti sve to prijenosom njihove moći na Božansku moć.
Just put it on the Divine power.
Samo ostavite to na božanskoj moći.
Now supposing I have a car which can drive Me down.
Sada pretpostavimo da imam auto koji me može voziti dolje.
So, if I have a car then I don’t put bullocks on it,
Dakle, ako imam auto onda ne stavljam na njega zapregu sa volovima,
that I don’t push My car, I just sit inside and use it.
ja ne guram moj auto, samo sjedim unutra i koristim ga.
In the same way, if you have this great power around you,
Na isti način, ako imate tu veliku moć oko sebe,
if your Sahasrara is absolutely, completely submerged in it,
ako je vaša Sahasrara apsolutno, potpuno uronjena u nju,
then you’ll be amazed how things work out for yourself.
onda ćete biti zaprepašteni kako stvari rade za vas.
I will give you an example of a Sahaja Yogi, he’s no more now,
Dat ću vam jedan primjer o Sahaja Yogiju, on nije više živ sada,
he was a fisherman, ordinary fisherman, but also he was educated,
bio je ribar, obični ribar, ali je bio i obrazovan,
so he was working in a bank.
tako da je radio u banci.
This one was going one day to do some Sahaja Yoga work
Krenuo on jednog dana da uradi neki sahaja Yoga posao
and he had to go by boat.
i morao je ići brodom.
So when he came out he saw that the whole place was clouded
Dakle, kada je izašao, vidio je da je cijelo mjesto oblačno
and it was about to burst out into a big havoc.
i da se spremalo prsnuti u veliku pustoš.
So he got very much perturbed about it that – “what is this?”
Pa je on postao jako uznemiren zbog toga što - „što je ovo”
Immediately, his Sahasrara was so open and good, immediately he said,
Odmah, Sahasrara mu je bila toliko otvorena i dobra, odmah je rekao,
“Now I leave it to this Divine power
„Sada ostavljam ovo Božanskoj moći
to stop all these things happening.
da zaustavi sve ovo da se desi.
I don’t want it to rain and to have any problem
Ne želim da pada kiša i da bude ikakvih problema
till I come back home and go off to sleep”.
dok sam se ne vratim kući i odem na spavanje.”
And it was surprising, people told Me that
I to je bilo iznenađujuće, ljudi su mi rekli da
“Mother, the clouds and everything were there
„Majko, oblaci i sve je tu
all throughout but it did not rain, did not do anything,
tijekom cijelog vremena ali nije padala kiša, nije ništa palo,
and there was no chaos of any kind”.
i nije bilo kaosa bilo koje vrste”.
He went to another island where he had to go,
Otišao je na drugi otok gdje je morao otići,
he did Sahaja Yoga and came back.
Bavio se sahađa jogom i vratio se.
And then when he went to sleep, then only,
I onda kad je otišao na spavanje, tek onda,
everything started pouring down.
sve je počelo polijevali dolje.
So, nature, everything, every leaf, every flower, everything,
Dakle, priroda, sve, svaki list, svaki cvijet, sve,
is worked out through the Divine power.
je razrađen kroz Božansku moć.
So we should not have our ego that we can do something ourselves,
Dakle, mi ne bi trebali imati naš ego da možemo nešto učiniti sami,
we can manage ourselves.
da možemo upravljati sami.
Once you have that kind of a thing,
Kada imate takvu stvar
you are not yet that much developed,
niste još uvek mnogo razvijeni,
you are not that much grown up in Sahaja Yoga.
niste toliko porasli u Sahaja Yogi.
But to grow up in Sahaja Yoga should not be difficult for you,
No, da porastete u Sahaja Yogi ne bi trebalo biti teško za vas,
because you have guidelines.
jer imate smjernice.
Those people who got their realization, very few of them,
Oni ljudi koji su dobili njihovu realizaciju, vrlo malo njih,
like Sufis and we had some saints in India, all of them;
poput sufija i imali smo neke svece u Indiji, svi oni;
how much they must have struggled.
koliko mora da su se borili.
Nobody to guide them, nobody to help them,
Nitko da ih vodi, nitko da im pomogne,
nobody to tell them about what they can achieve.
nitko da im kaže što mogu postići.
And despite that they were very satisfied people,
I unatoč tome oni su bili vrlo zadovoljni ljudi,
very happy people, and they worked it out so well.
vrlo sretni ljudi, i oni su radili tako dobro.
They saw the whole world with another angle, as you can also see,
Vidjeli su cijeli svijet s drugog kuta, kao što možete vidjeti,
but they were not upset and they had such self-confidence,
ali oni nisu bili uznemireni i imali su takvo samopouzdanje,
they had such knowledge of their own
imali su takvo znanje sebe
that they achieved through their meditative process.
koje su postigli kroz meditativni proces.
And the way they have written books,
I način na koji su napisali knjige,
some of them are so great, it’s very surprisingly,
neki od njih su toliko veliki, to je vrlo iznenađujuće,
how they have achieved these great verses, such full of knowledge.
kako su postigli ove velike stihove, tako pune znanja.
One cannot understand that they had no guidance,
Teško je shvatiti da nisu imali vođstvo,
nobody was to tell them.
nije bilo nikoga da im kažem.
But one thing with them was
Ali jedna stvar sa njima je bila
that they always tried to look after their Sahasrara.
da su uvijek nastojali da se brinu o svojoj Sahasrari.
Now one thing is there obstructing Sahasrara
Sad jedna stvar tu opstruira Sahasraru
is the movement of your Agnya into thoughts.
je kretanje vaše Agnje u misli.
That’s the only thing, that’s the only thing
To je jedina stvar, to je jedina stvar
that stops your entry into Sahaja Yoga.
koji zaustavlja vaš ulazak u Sahaja Yogu.
Thoughts are coming all the time,
Misli dolaze cijelo vrijeme,
because a human being is born who reacts to everything,
jer ljudsko biće se rađa i koje reagira na sve,
react to this and react to that
reagirati na ovo i reagirati na to
and the thoughts come in and the thoughts go.
i misli dolaze i misli odlaze.
There’s a big crowd of thoughts.
Postoji velika gomila misli.
Because of that your attention cannot cross over Agnya
Zbog toga vaša pažnja se ne može preći preko Agnye
and can reside in the Sahasrara.
i nalaziti se u Sahasrari.
So first of all, one should see what sort of thoughts are coming.
Dakle, prije svega, treba vidjeti kakve misli dolaze.
You have to condemn yourself sometimes.
Morate se osuditi ponekad.
You have to say: “What nonsense! What have I been doing?
Morate reći: „Kakva glupost! Što sam radio?
What’s the matter with me? How could I do all that?”
Što nije u redu sa mnom? Kako sam mogao učiniti sve to?”
Once you start doing that, these thoughts will start disappearing.
Jednom kada počnete to raditi, te misli će početi nestajati.
These thoughts are coming from two angles,
Ove misli dolaze iz dva kuta,
one from the ego and another from your conditionings.
jedan od ega i još jedan od vaših uvjetovanosti.
And these are so much built up within you,
I one su toliko ugrađene u vama,
that they don’t allow your agnya to be crossed.
da one ne dopuštaju da se pređe vaša agnya.
That’s why we have two Bija mantras of ‘Hum’, ‘Kshum’.
Zato imamo dve biđa mantre: „Ham”, „Kšam”.
First one is, when it is conditioning,
Prva je, kada je uvjetovanost,
you are endowed with this kind of a fear,
vi ste obdareni sa ovom vrstom straha,
“I shouldn’t do like this, I shouldn’t do like that,
„Ne bi trebalo napraviti ovako, ne bih trebao onako,
it’s not allowed, that is not allowed.”
to nije dozvoljeno, ono nije dopušteno.”
That’s the conditioning part of it.
To je dio uvjetovanosti.
Conditioning can be of many types.
Uvjetovanost može biti od mnogih vrsta.
But the ego part of it is that,
No, deo ega je to da,
“I must overpower everybody, I must get this,
„Moram nadvladati sve, moram nabaviti to,
I must be able to rule everyone.”
Moram biti u stanju vladati svima.”
These two things are there in the mind
Ove dvije stvari su tu u glavi
which are all the time crossing over.
koje cijelo vrijeme prelaze.
So it’s important that we should go into thoughtless awareness
Dakle, važno je da trebamo ući u stanje svijesti bez misli
and that thoughtless awareness is the real way
i to stanje bez misli je pravi put
that your Sahasrara can be nourished by the Kundalini.
da vašu Sahasraru može hraniti Kundalini.
Because Kundalini cannot go through, it cannot pass through.
Budući da Kundalini ne može proći, ne može proći kroz Agnju.
And for that, as I said, there are two Bija mantras,
A za to, kao što sam rekla, postoje dvije Biđa mantre,
one is ‘Hum’ another ’Kshum’.
jedna je „Ham” druga „Kšam”.
So, if you are conditioned, you are frightened,
Dakle, ako su uvjetovani, vi ste uplašeni,
you are afraid and you had ideas about yourself.
vi se bojite i imate ideje o sebi.
These days the way people are describing, they’ll say,
Ovih dana na način na koji ljudi opisuju, oni će reći:
“I’m an extrovert”.
„Ja sam ekstrovertna osoba”.
Somebody will say, “I’m an introvert”,
Netko će reći: „Ja sam introvert”
somebody will say “I’m a hippie”, “I’m that”, I’m that.
netko će reći: „Ja sam hipi”, „Ja sam to”, ja sam taj.
All kinds of things they can have attributed to themselves.
Svakakve stvari koje oni mogu pripisati sebi.
But these ideas are all coming from outside, they are not from inside.
No, ove ideje sve dolaze izvana, one nisu iznutra.
To get to the inner side of yourself, the subtler side of your being,
Da biste došli do unutarnje strane sebe, suptilnije strane vašeg bića,
you must allow the Kundalini to go through the Agnya.
morate omogućiti Kundalini da prođe kroz Agnya čakru.
And to cross the Agnya is a very important thing
A prijeći Agnya je vrlo važna stvar
in modern times and for that you have to meditate.
u modernim vremenima i za to morate meditirati.
If you can meditate with complete faith in yourself
Ako možete meditirati uz potpunu vjeru u sebe
this Agnya can be opened out.
ova Agnya se može otvoriti.
With surrendering to the Divine,
S prepuštanjem Božanskom,
you have to surrender yourself to the Divine.
morate se predati Božanskom.
And when this Agnya opens, you’ll be amazed,
A kada se ova Agnya otvori, vi ćete biti zaprepašteni,
your Sahasrara is just waiting to transfer,
Vaš Sahasrara samo čeka za prijenos,
to give you all the help that you need through the All-pervading Power.
da vam da svu pomoć koja vam je potrebna kroz sveprožimajuću moć.
Your connection of Sahasrara with
Vaša veza u Sahasrari sa
the All-pervading Power is established.
sveprožimajučim moći je uspostavljena.
And by that you’ll be amazed how all these seven chakras work for you,
I da ćete biti zaprepašteni kako će svih sedam čakri raditi za vas,
how they help you, how they try to give you whatever
kako vam pomažu, kako one pokušavaju dati što god
is the real knowledge about everything.
je pravo znanje o svemu.
This real knowledge that you get is very joy giving.
To pravo znanje koje ste dobili daje puno radosti.
You can see this real knowledge in everything.
Možete vidjeti ovo pravo znanje u svemu.
You don’t have to start reading any book about it.
Ne morate početi da čitati bilo koju knjigu o tome.
In every situation and in every person, in every flower,
U svakoj situaciji i u svakom čovjeku, u svakom cvijetu,
in every natural happening, you see clearly the hand of the Divine.
u svakom prirodnom događaju, vidjet ćete jasno ruku Božanskog.
Once you see the hand of the Divine your egos start disappearing.
Kada vidite ruku Božanskog vaš će ego početi nestajati.
Once you say that “It’s You. You do everything.”
Nakon što kažete: „To si ti. Ti učiniti sve.”
Kabira has said something great about this,
Kabira je rekao nešto veliko o tome,
he said that when the goat is alive it goes on saying
On je rekao da kada je koza živa, ona ide govoreći
“Mai, mai” - “I am, I am”.
„Mai Mai” - „Ja sam, ja sam”.
But when it is slaughtered and its intestines are made into strings,
No, kad se zakolje i njene iznutrice naprave u žice,
which are used for cleaning the cotton, then it said
koje se koriste za čišćenje pamuka, onda govori:
“tuhi, tuhi” - “you are, you are, you are”.
„Tuhi, tuhi” - „ti si, ti si, ti si”.
See, in this symbolic way, they have suggested that:
Vidite, na ovaj simboličan način, oni su sugerirali da:
you have to become dissolved into this Divine power.
se morate "otopiti" u ovoj božanskoj moći.
“It’s the Divine power that does everything. What am I?
„To je Božanska moć koja radi sve. Što sam ja?
I was just a drop and I fell into this ocean of awareness
Bio sam samo kap, i kap je pala u ocean svijesti
of the Divine power and that is taking over and working it out.”
Božanske snage, te  ona preuzima i razrešava stvari.”
That will help you a lot to be a great Sahaja Yogi.
To će vam pomoći puno da budete veliki Sahaja Yogi.
You developed curing powers, but still you are not proud of it.
Razvili ste sposobnosti lečenja, ali još uvijek niste ponosni. toga
You developed, of course, awakening powers, you are not proud of it.
Razvili ste, naravno, moći buđenja, niste ponosni na to.
You develop so many creative powers and you are not proud of it.
Možete razviti tolike stvaralačke moći i niste ponosni.
You become really very, very creative, extremely creative.
Vi postanete stvarno vrlo, vrlo kreativni, izuzetno kreativni.
But the greatest thing happend to you
Ali najveća stvar se dogodila vama
that you become a global personality.
da postanete globalna osobnost.
So you start seeing the problem of every country,
Dakle, počnete videti ​​problem svake zemlje,
of every other nation where they have problems.
od svakog drugog naroda, gdje oni imaju probleme.
But these problems, when you see, you don’t see like other people.
Ali ti problemi, kada ih vidite, ne vidi kao i ostali ljudi.
Because others may like to use it for their own purpose,
Budući da drugi možda žele iskoristiti to za vlastite potrebe,
maybe for media, maybe for something.
možda za medije, možda za nešto.
But what you want to see is that these problems are solved.
No, ono što želite vidjeti je da su ti problemi riješeni.
You see, your powers are so great, with this kind of a mind,
Vidite, vaše moći su tako velike, s ovom vrstom uma,
I would say, which is dominated completely by the Divine power,
Rekla bih, kojeg dominira u potpunosti Božanska moć,
that it, whatever disturbs you,
da, što god ti smeta,
immediately it’s taken over and it starts working out.
odmah je preuzeto i počinje rešavati.
Many, many problems have been solved by Sahaja Yoga
Mnogi, mnogi problemi su riješeni Sahaja Yogom
and also they can be solved on a very universal level,
i oni se mogu riješiti na vrlo univerzalnoj razini,
if you are a global person.
ako ste globalna osoba.
If you are a global person then
Ako ste globalna osoba onda
what happens is that you become a, sort of a, vehicle,
što se događa je da ste postali, neka vrsta, vozila,
or you can become like a channel for this Divine power
ili možete postati poput kanala za ovu božansku moć
to act because you are purely a global personality.
da djeluje zato što ste čisto globalna osoba.
Not attached to this, attached to that,
Niste vezani na to, za ovo,
but a pure Sahaja personality which can be used
ali čista Sahaja ličnost koja može koristiti
by this Divine power very easily.
ovoj Božanskoj moći vrlo lako.